The Huben Army's ambush
caused Chang'an to fall.
The Emperor, Xiao Wuyang, was attacked
and went missing.
Yan Fengshan rules Chang'an once again.
Master, is this the only way
out of the city?
Yes.
A few thousand people were mobilized
from Hidden Soldier Alley.
They mainly handle court secrets
and the city gates.
The canal is remote
so there is still a chance.
People say that Your Majesty
is kind in heart yet lacking in talent.
You ascended the throne
only to govern in mediocrity.
You brought war back upon the land
and left the common people in misery.
They also added that, in the end,
you had let your ancestors down
and perished in disgrace.
But I beg to differ.
I have heard that
under Your Majesty's leadership,
you granted the people time to recover
and returned the troops to their barracks.
You reshaped customs
and brought prosperity to all.
The elderly had someone to rely on
and the children had someone
to raise them.
Though your reign
lacked both the fierce valor
of your late father
and the martial might
of the Marquis of Northguard,
you held compassion for the common folk,
and cared for the livelihood of the poor.
With such devotion to the state
and its people,
you are not at fault.
They called you a scoundrel
whose disorderly governance
caused the northern army to rise
and seize the throne by force.
The court cowered in trepidation
and the martial world grew disheartened.
Fear stirred resentment
and bitterness took root
against Your Majesty.
While Your Majesty
might have lost your throne
and is wandering the world aimlessly,
your devotion shouldn't be confined
only to the palace walls.
Even far from the center of power,
you may still accomplish much.
In this life,
I fear I will have no chance
to see Your Majesty again.
I pray only that Your Majesty
does not forget your first intent…
FROM HAN ZILING
…for one day it will be heard
somewhere in the world.
So your name was Han Ziling.
For some reason,
the gates of the Imperial Jail are open.
I guess
White Hair has fulfilled his promise.
You've been sitting for a few decades.
You can finally stand up now.
I no longer have the right to sit.
To save you,
I hid the fact
that White Hair
was in Hidden Soldier Alley.
This is unfair
to the Huben Army.
To protect myself,
I even gave away
the Huben Army's gold coin.
This is also a form of betrayal.
Mother,
like mother, like son indeed.
Right now,
the Huben Army
no longer has anything to do with me.
I think
I should leave.
I should have
left sooner.
ONE MONTH LATER
Hot lamb soup!
-Come inside.
-Come in.
-Yes.
-Two?
-Sir, sit down.
-It's fresh.
-More vegetables.
-It's delicious.
-Sure.
-It's so fresh.
Give me some.
Here.
Sure. Let me pack it for you.
-Who are you?
-It's me.
Don't you remember me?
‎HOUSE SAUCES
Little runt, right?
You are a little runt.
Indeed.
I don't know who my parents are.
Perhaps I'm someone no one wants.
Come and have a look.
I was just kidding.
Give me two jin of pork shoulder.
My mother's making
stuffed flatbread tonight.
Oh, it's you.
Why not get some?
I'm sorry. I can't help you this time.
Why?
Didn't you go to the butcher's shop
to chop some meat for me last time?
That was the last time.
This time, it's different.
How so?
I'm different.
You still look the same.
Did you commit a crime?
A huge crime.
Then, can you still go home and eat?
I guess.
However, I'm different.
I have to earn
my own meal.
That is why it's so meaningful.
General, dinner is ready.
Let's wait for Wang Pu.
He has gone to the market.
He'll be slow with shackles on his feet.
You may go back first.
One more thing.
Secret envoys of Tiemo have departed.
Yang Chuhao
is in charge of taking care of them.
The Tiemo people are coming.
White Hair should also be appearing soon.
He won't let go of this opportunity.
Tell Yang Chuhao's men
to keep a close eye on it.
Yes.
Why hasn't Wang Pu come back?
I'll go and pick him up from the market.
You spoil him, General.
I captured Chang'an
but I didn't sit on the throne
at Taiqing Hall.
I moved to the market instead.
But eating alone makes me feel lonely.
I'm closing up.
-The radish is nice.
-Do you have something larger?
-They are different.
-That's great.
Very good.
-I'll take two.
-Sure.
Give me a discount.
I want more.
-General.
Keep drinking.
All of you may leave.
I have something to say to Mr. Wang Pu.
-Yes.
When you're upset,
drinking makes you inebriated faster.
I dare not act recklessly before you.
You've acted recklessly many times.
Zhiying cooks for us every day.
She never complains,
yet you will not accept her kindness.
I'm not refusing her kindness.
I feel too guilty to eat.
Do you feel no guilt
eating meat and drinking wine
in this eatery, then?
Back in Hidden Soldier Alley,
I gave him plenty of favors.
Of course, I don't feel guilty.
On the contrary,
I failed to solve your problem
and nearly cost you your life.
I feel guilty.
You won't win against White Hair.
I might not even be able to do it either.
Zhiying said I spoiled you.
I don't treat you
like a general treats his subordinates.
However, you served me
since you were young.
I've never regarded you as my subordinate.
If a subordinate makes a mistake
and I kill him,
many more people are available
to obey my command.
When you make a mistake
and don't come home to eat,
I come out to find you.
I endure the night breeze,
as though looking for my own child.
It's time to go back.
-You're paying for real?
-Of course.
I won't kill you
just because you charged me.
Look.
The reward is quite high.
I know, right?
Have you seen this man?
If I'd seen him, I would've…
Let's go.
WARRANT
It does not resemble him.
Master, I'm back.
It's time to go back.
It's going to rain soon.
We're going back when I just arrived?
Let's rest for a while longer.
The air is good here,
unlike the gloomy
and depressing Cangshui River.
It's stuffy there.
Master,
what is the tale behind Cangshui River?
I've been keeping watch from inside
for a few days.
And I noticed some suspicious people.
You are always keeping an eye on others.
They will think
you are the suspicious one too.
I have to do that.
You know who I'm protecting.
Huai'an's father, Liu Ziwen,
is a rare talent.
He spent his whole life
protecting Chang'an.
Hidden Soldier Alley
is the last line of defense.
When it fails and Chang'an falls,
the people and the government
have to move to Cangshui River.
Unfortunately,
before Cangshui River was built,
he was killed.
Does Yan Fengshan know about this place?
Or is there anyone in the Huben Army
who knows about this?
I am the manager of Cangshui River.
Do you think I'm foolish enough
to let Yan Fengshan
and the others know about it?
I know you are the manager.
Aren't we just having a friendly chat?
Moreover,
looking at you now,
you are just a boatman at most.
I manage everything from this boat.
You can only reach Cangshui River
on this boat using this river.
Cangshui River only houses refugees now.
All of them have their lips sealed.
No need to be wary of them.
All right.
With you as the manager,
I'm relieved.
I'm leaving.
Take care. Go on.
Just leave it here.
Yes.
-Give it to me.
-No.
-Your salary.
-It's my turn.
-Pile them up.
-Just hold it.
-How many doses of this?
-Weigh your herbs first.
Slow down.
Sir!
I'm done moving the goods.
You've worked hard.
Young men are indeed strong.
With you around,
I can take it easy.
Sir,
have you noticed
someone looking at the shop all the time?
They are just staring
from right outside the shop.
Although they don't stand there for long,
do you think
there's something in this shop
that attracts attention?
Young man,
how long have you been working here?
I've been here for quite some time.
I was working in other shops
and you were hiring.
I came here because you paid more.
You are lying.
I…
I'm not lying.
It's all right.
Everyone who comes here
is a person in misfortune.
Everyone has it tough.
It's normal to keep everything
to yourself.
I'm sure that you just arrived
at Cangshui River.
Why don't you tell me
what time it is now?
They are here
to look at this.
Okay.
Along the streets,
there are many of these.
I wonder which smart guy invented this.
Anyway, when I acquired this shop,
it was already here.
That's right.
From tomorrow onward,
you must scoop up the salt that leaks out
and pour it back in.
But I still need to move the goods.
Not anymore. Just watch the shop for me.
Really?
Tomorrow.
Sure!
My back is sore
from moving the goods every day.
My shoulders are sore.
You seem too delicate.
You must once have been of noble birth.
But I don't have a noble's fate.
I was just a pageboy.
A pageboy?
I'll get it again when I finish it.
Take a look.
Here you go.
Look at my chicken.
-How many doses…
-Give me a discount…
-…a day?
-…sir.
Weigh your medicine first.
This is far too dear.
You're back?
How's your brother?
Just like that.
I worked many jobs
and I still can't make a lot of money.
This is tough.
A few days in and you're already
complaining.
Listen.
This is life.
Life?
Life also demands…
That's right. Starting tomorrow,
I'll be taking care of the salt shop.
Someone needs to move the goods.
If you go there,
we'll have two people
working two jobs and earning two salaries.
Good idea.
Working two jobs and earning two salaries.
We may even afford wine.
As expected of you.
No, thanks.
Who was the one who said
this was life just now?
I said that was your life.
I don't like your job
and you can't do my job.
I wonder how Huai'an is doing now.
XUANDU TEMPLE
If you hadn't been transferred
out of Chang'an,
we wouldn't have this opportunity
to have tea so casually.
Yet coming here
only fills me with disappointment.
You've been in Chang'an for so many years.
Don't you have any other ways?
Ways?
After Yan Fengshan captured Chang'an,
the whole situation changed.
What ways do I have?
‎AWAKEN TO THE TRUE WAY
But I heard nothing has changed
in the imperial court.
General Fengshan
doesn't even enter Taiqing Hall.
He even brought someone
from the Xiao imperial family
to be the Emperor
to preserve the legitimacy
of the Xiao dynasty.
Do you really think that the young emperor
is from the Xiao family?
Whether I believe in it or not
isn't important.
The important thing
is when you can be transferred
back to Chang'an.
I'll be honest with you.
On the surface,
I was only an Imperial Guard.
In truth,
I was actually serving Chancellor Gao.
Now, Chancellor Gao
is doing worse than I am.
What makes you think
I can make a comeback again?
Nothing is absolute in life.
It's full of ups and downs.
Don't dwell on it.
When your next wave of fortune comes,
you might even go to further heights.
If your temple had more devotees,
I might believe you a little more.
Look at it now.
It sees more flies than devotees.
It's not a popular area.
Enough.
Just stay here.
When I come here tomorrow,
I'll get another cup of tea.
-Take care.
-Farewell.
XUANDU TEMPLE
LIVE BY NATURE'S WAY
Zeng, the wind rises.
Remember to sleep with an extra blanket.
Yes.
It's getting windy.
No need to worry about me.
I can protect myself.
Thank you for guarding the temple.
I was able to go home for a few nights.
If you need anything, just tell me.
Don't stand on ceremony.
Thank you for taking me in.
You will be blessed for your kindness.
XUANDU TEMPLE
You're here.
It has been a long time.
However, this move is too dangerous.
Last time,
we lost badly.
A visitor this late at night?
An acquaintance came to visit.
We exchanged a few words.
I see.
I've returned to retrieve some lamp oil.
Has your friend left?
He has.
He left in a hurry.
You look very tired.
You must rest more.
Sure.
Give me more time.
I will soon give you an explanation.
Liu Zhi,
I don't need an explanation.
I just want you
to live on.
Live on?
What meaning is there in living?
CHANGLE OUTPOST
Sir,
instead of sleeping at night,
you stare at this warrant.
WARRANT
Do you know him?
Your opportunity to return to Chang'an
is here.
It's the middle of the night.
Don't try to fool me.
Last month, gave someone shelter.
He said his name was Zeng.
He came to Chang'an to do business
and all his money was scammed.
He asked for a place to stay.
I told him to work at the temple
as a night guard
so that I can sneak out
at night to gamble.
Sir,
do you know how much you have lost?
Why persist in gambling?
But now,
I think he looks like this person.
Last month?
Why didn't you say it sooner?
Is your vision so bad
that you only noticed yesterday?
Of course not.
I recognized him long ago
but I also heard about what he did
in Chang'an back then.
He is the man chosen by Xiao Wuyang.
I need to determine
what the right thing to do is.
In the future,
if Xiao Wuyang rises again,
then I shouldn't
offend this person as well.
How unexpected.
You are more shrewd than I expected.
Today, he looked all dazed
like he was talking to ghosts.
He has no future left.
It's better to turn him in
and make us both rich.
We'll get 1,000 liang of silver.
You can take the credit.
But I have been unlucky recently.
Your bad luck must've rubbed off on me.
I even owe a lot of debt.
I just need a way back to the Capital.
You can
take all the reward.
WARRANT
Hot lamb soup!
Move.
Let's go.
-Yes.
-Give me two.
-Sir, take a seat.
-Fresh from the pot.
Vegetables! Come and take a look!
Fresh lamb meat!
Sir, two bowls of mutton.
Sure.
Sir, enjoy.
RICE BALLS, SWEETS, HOUSE SAUCES
-Come and take a look.
-Mom, I want to drink the soup.
Pick it up, quick.
Come and take a look!
Buns!
-Meat buns!
-They are fresh.
They are delicious!
Miss, come.
-How about two?
-Come out and eat some meat.
You've trailed me all morning.
Nothing can be hidden
from you, Mr. Wang.
Let's talk while we eat.
Then I shall help myself.
In the past,
I was an Imperial Guard on the surface
but I was actually serving the chancellor.
Chancellor Gao?
How are his legs?
Worse than yours by far.
Continue.
Xie Huai'an was stabbed previously.
Chancellor Gao ordered me
to protect Xie Huai'an,
Ye Zheng, and Zhang Mo.
I was with them for a few years.
Other people don't recognize them
but I do.
Who did you find?
The Taoist temple outside the city.
Xie Huai'an.
I speak truth.
If I lie to you,
I don't think it'll be difficult
for you to kill me, Mr. Wang.
However, your former master,
Chancellor Gao,
is very protective of Xie Huai'an.
When the ship sinks, everyone jumps.
In recent times,
one's wealth is more important
than one's reputation.
Being loyal is not as practical
as having some lamb meat to eat.
Sir.
Coming.
That's too much.
Buy a knife with the extra change.
Let's go.
Stop.
Mr. Wang Pu.
What's wrong?
The weather is changing.
XUANDU TEMPLE
THE WAY LIVES ON
Just one person?
Shut up.
Do you know who he is?
Mr. Wang Pu
is the most capable person
under General Fengshan.
Apologies for not recognizing you.
Forgive me.
That's enough. Where is he?
He's in the hall at the back.
He said his name was Zeng.
He has been staying here
for about a month.
Don't follow me.
I'll go inside alone.
AWAKENING AND RETURNING TO PURITY
You're here?
Yes.
I'm cooking dumplings.
I made some for you too.
Sure. I'll dine with you.
I know you want to earn merit
and regain your dignity
in front of Yan Fengshan.
Thus,
I asked Commander Wang to lure you here.
He serves me.
I know that.
He plays his part quite well.
Right.
I can't hide it from you for too long.
You're here.
It has been a while.
I've been waiting for you to summon me.
Another move has to be made
to hit back against Yan Fengshan.
I will never forget
what the chancellor did for me.
As long as I can avenge the chancellor
and kill the Huben Army,
I will do your bidding.
I'm a criminal.
The general had a few men around me
to prevent me from escaping.
But after Commander Wang appeared
and I left the city with him,
they stopped appearing.
That means your men in the city
removed those sentries.
You are indeed the smartest tactician
under Yan Fengshan.
The dumplings will be done soon.
Have patience.
Stop flattering me.
I was completely outwitted by you
at Hidden Soldier Alley.
Then you know
full well
I stand as your opponent.
You also know that this is a trap.
Why come here at all?
Why not?
When I found out
you were keeping an eye on me,
I couldn't wait to stand before you
and see what tricks you had prepared.